Part 2. You will hear a short talk given to a group of retired people about a club called Connect.
First you have some time to look at questions 11 to 15.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 15.
Hello, I've been asked to talk to you today about Connect. Connect is a club for people who have retired from full-time work.
The first Connect club began back in 1960 in Brisbane, Australia.
Today I'll concentrate on Frankston Connect, the club where I'm a member. It services the communities around the suburb of Frankston here in Melbourne.
Okay, so what are our club aims? We're not a fitness club or anything like that. Some Connect branches do charity work, but that's not for us.
Our objective is to provide social contact with others who have similar interests and ideas.
Now meetings, we have monthly club meetings where the usual club business is discussed.
For example, at the last meeting we talked about how much money was spent that month.
Also at that meeting someone had just returned from an overseas trip and he spoke about that.
Then we looked at entries for our photography competition. The winner will be announced soon.
Up until now we've used the school hall for our meetings, but that's about to be renovated so we needed to find an alternative.
It's been a great venue because of its size and it's so easy to get to, but I'm sure historical Frankston Hall will suit us just fine.
Our social committee plans and organises club trips from time to time and they're always looking for suggestions from members for new places to go to.
If you join you should check the activities list that's posted on a website each month and attend anything that interests you.
Come and make friends we're just one big happy family.
So how do you join and what about membership fees? It's simple. Just fill in the form and give it to me before you leave this morning.
There are a few payment options. Some members prefer to make an annual payment which is a slightly cheaper option or you can pay monthly.
Why don't you get a group together it makes the activities more fun.
Before you hear the rest of the talk you have some time to look at questions 16 to 20.
Now listen and answer a question 16 to 20.
If you still haven't decided whether to join or not let me try to tempt you with some of our upcoming events.
Our moonlight wildlife walk was previously available to members immediate families as well.
But this wonderful activities become so popular that it's now limited to just members.
Although it's free we do ask our members to pay something to the wildlife fund so it can continue its good work.
Everyone makes their way to the wildlife park independently arriving at dusk where a guide walks with the group and tells us about all the animals we encounter.
Okay theater in the park we see a different play every month.
The parks on the train line and easy to access so we don't organise buses or anything.
Come along and recline on a blanket on the grass although some members prefer to take along their own seat.
No need to make a reservation there's plenty of space.
After the play we all walk to a local cafe where you can purchase coffee and cake. It's a really fun night out.
Birdwatching is a regular activity and it's organised by the keen bird watches in the club.
This activity consists mainly of early morning and late afternoon walking trips to spot the birds when they're most active.
Birdwatching attracts only small numbers so one of our ardent birdwatches drives members in the club van to the best spots.
The City Botanical Gardens Walk is a popular activity that occurs a couple of times a year.
Members make their own way there and usually meet up outside the gates at 8.45am setting off for the hours walk with the volunteer guide by 9am.
Many members bring a friend or relative and this is fine.
Now the state library our visits here in the past have always been great because there's something for everyone.
You can easily spend a whole day in there.
There's a lovely restaurant and you can take food into the small cinema there where we'll be watching a short film about the history of our local area.
That is the end of part 2. You now have 30 seconds to check your answers to part 2.
You
Hello, I've been asked to talk to you today about Connect.
Connect is a club for people who have retired from full-time work.
The first Connect club began back in 1960 in Brisbane, Australia.
Today, I'll concentrate on Frankston Connect, the club where I'm a member.
It services the communities around the suburb of Frankston here in Melbourne.
Okay, so what are our club aims?
We're not a fitness club or anything like that.
Some Connect branches do charity work, but that's not for us.
Our objective is to provide social contact with others who have similar interests and ideas.
Now, meetings. We have monthly club meetings where the usual club business is discussed.
For example, at the last meeting, we talked about how much money was spent that month.
Also at that meeting, someone had just returned from an overseas trip and he spoke about that.
Then we looked at entries for our photography competition. The winner will be announced soon.
Up until now, we've used the school hall for our meetings.
But that's about to be renovated, so we needed to find an alternative.
It's been a great venue because of its size and it's so easy to get to,
but I'm sure historical Frankston Hall will suit us just fine.
Our social committee plans and organises club trips from time to time,
and they're always looking for suggestions from members for new places to go to.
If you join, you should check the activities list that's posted on a website each month
and attend anything that interests you.
Come and make friends where just one big happy family.
So, how do you join and what about membership fees?
It's simple. Just fill in the form and give it to me before you leave this morning.
There are a few payment options.
Some members prefer to make an annual payment, which is a slightly cheaper option,
or you can pay monthly. Why don't you get a group together?
It makes the activities more fun.
If you still haven't decided whether to join or not,
let me try to tempt you with some of our upcoming events.
Our Moonlight Wildlife Walk was previously available to members immediate families as well.
But this wonderful activities become so popular that it's now limited to just members.
Although it's free, we do ask our members to pay something to the Wildlife Fund so it can continue its good work.
Everyone makes their way to the Wildlife Park independently,
arriving at dusk, where a guide walks with the group and tells us about all the animals we encounter.
Okay, theater in the park. We see a different play every month.
The park's on the train line and easy to access, so we don't organise buses or anything.
Come along and recline on a blanket on the grass,
although some members prefer to take along their own seat.
No need to make a reservation. There's plenty of space.
After the play, we all walk to a local cafe where you can purchase coffee and cake.
It's a really fun night out.
Birdwatching is a regular activity and it's organised by the keen bird watches in the club.
This activity consists mainly of early morning and late afternoon walking trips to spot the birds when they're most active.
Birdwatching attracts only small numbers, so one of our ardent bird watches drives members in the club van to the best spots.
The City Botanical Gardens Walk is a popular activity that occurs a couple of times a year.
Members make their own way there and usually meet up outside the gates at 8.45am,
setting off for the hours walk with the volunteer guide by 9am.
Many members bring a friend or relative and this is fine.
Now, the state library. Our visits here in the past have always been great because there's something for everyone.
You can easily spend a whole day in there.
There's a lovely restaurant and you can take food into the small cinema there
where we'll be watching a short film about the history of our local area.